Guide to the Myrte Rice Haynes genealogical papers, 1909-1954.
Haynes, Myrte Rice genealogical papers, 1909-1954.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Myrte Rice Haynes genealogical papers, 1909-1954.
1805
Myrte Rice Haynes, d. 1957.
.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, notes, notebooks, newspaper clippings, and pamphlets.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence about genealogical matters, undated notes and notebooks on genealogy of the Rice and related families, heraldry, genealogical methodology and bibliography; newspaper clippings, and eight pamphlets on genealogy and history.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence about genealogical matters, undated notes and notebooks on genealogy of the Rice and related families, heraldry, genealogical methodology and bibliography; newspaper clippings, and eight pamphlets on genealogy and history.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Haynes, Myrte Rice, d. 1957.; Rice family.
Subjects:
Genealogy.; Genealogists.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence 1909-1921 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence 1924-1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence 1927-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence 1946-1954, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Notes - C-H: Cady, Cheever, Clark, Coffin, Dean, Dey, Doty, Dowd, Eastman, Fonda, Foster, Gaylor, Gaylord, Gouger, Hall, Hammond, Hart, Hayward, Hoff, Howard (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Previous guide also mentions the Ammerman, Bloom, Bowen, and Cady families.
- Notes - J-M: Joslyn, Judd, Kimball, King, Luce, Merry, Moore (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Notes - N-P: Newton, Norton, Owen, Pulsipher (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Notes - R-S: Rice, Roberts, Sisson, Sperry, Stratton (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Notes - W: Ware, Warren, Weatherby, White, Whitmore, Winne, Winter, Wood (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Histories of New York, Pennsylvania, Connecticut (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Newspaper and magazine clippings on Rochester history, genealogy, heraldry (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Genealogical notes - various families (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Notes on genealogical methodology, bibliographies, heraldry and other matters related to the study of genealogy, "Genealogy Round Table" (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Genealogy notes (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
- William Throop and Adrian Scrope - The Family Tradition - History of the Scrope Family and the Barony of Bolton - Bolton Castle - Proceedings at the Trial of Adrian Scrope - The Regicides and the Ancestral Chart of Adrian Scrope, Research and Narrative by Evelyn Fish Knudson. Privately Printed, 1943: By Addison James Throop and Dan Addison Throop, East St. Louis, Illinois. 74 pp. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  In back is table of ancestry in hand of M.R.H. tracing ancestry of Paul Rice back ten generations to William Throope.
- American Ancestry: American Ancestors of Barbara Evelyn Bowen, Harold King Bowen (Osceola, Mo., 1944 ) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- The Sullivan Expedition of 1779, Albert Hazen Wright (Ithaca, 1943 ) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Sampler (photocopy): Paul Whitmore Rice chart (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Accordion File: alphabetically arranged newsclippings re: family names (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "First Commencement Exercises of the Univ. of the Philippines," Program, Mar. 29, 1911
- Book of Adam, Henry King Bowen
- The Story of Irondequoit Bay, Katherine W. Thompson (Penfield, N.Y. ?, 1956 )
- Ancestral Notes from Chedwato, Charles D. & Edna W. Townsend, Edit. & Pub., Vol. 2, #6, Nov. 1955
- Northamptonshire, Past & Present, The Northamptonshire Record Society, Pub. (Northamptonshire, England, 1955 )